Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer London, United Kingdom +44 7487 553781 konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

Profile

Self-motivated Software Developer with six years of experience including over five years of experience in Java development. I would like to participate in true teamwork and develop well-tested applications using a continuous delivery approach. I enjoy doing deep investigations, learning new technologies, and always looking for ways to do things better.

EXPERIENCE

Monese

London, United Kingdom

Mar 2019 - Present

Software Engineer

- Reduced costs by systematically working to improve software performance and decrease their operating costs. For one application, it's monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.
- Increased revenue by doggedly identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a fix for a single customer led to identifying a significant gap in profit.
- Pricing: Researched regarding breaking monolithic responsibility micro-services. Refactored and developed the
 pricing structure of the system. Delivered business priorities by completing new annual pricing functionality
 on-time and without any significant issues.
- Joint Accounts: Designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese
Software Engineer

Tallinn, Estonia
Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- Smart Transactions: Improved scalability of micro-services by separating read and write operation of the
 database. Migrated gradually 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service. Decreased average
 response time from 60ms to 5ms. Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling.
 Helped to improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- Recurring Payments: Designed and developed a micro-service with test coverage of up to 80%.
- Tools: Java 8-11, Angular, TypeScript, Grails, Scala, Docker, Amazon AWS, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Google API, Mockito, Junit, Redis, AWS, CloudWatch, New Relic, Jenkins, Git, Intellij, Groovy, Testcontainers, Maven, Liquibase, Bootstrap, macOS

• Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia

Software Developer

Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

- Developed an internet banking website which is used by 2M customers.
- o Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.
- o Tools: Java 8, RiotJS, Selenium, Mockito, TDD, Intellij, Agile, extreme programming, Play! Framework, Ubuntu

• Knowit
Software Developer

Tallinn, Estonia

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

- Developed a full-stack web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.
- **Technologies**: AngularJS, Java 8, Docker, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JHipster, Sass, CSS3, HTML5, Protractor, Maven, Liquibase, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Ubuntu, Git

EDUCATION

• Tallinn University

Estonia

Bachelor of Scinece in Engineering (BSc); Computer Science; GPA: 4.73/5; cum laude

2014 - 2017